<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep Learning | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/deep-learning/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Deep Learning</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/deep-learning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Encryption</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/cripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/cripts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In public-key encryption, each party creates a pair of keys, a public key and a private key. These keys are linked to each other, so a message encrypted with the public key can only be decrypted with the corresponding private key.
An important point is that when creating keys, it is possible to generate very large numbers in such a way that, knowing the public key, it is impossible to calculate the private key in any way. Thus, ensuring reliable encryption of messages is based on the knowledge of the private key exclusively by its owner. The idea of asymmetric encryption is based on a complex mathematical question that allows you to build one-way functions. Given x, the function y = f(x) is easily determined. But at the same time, it is very difficult to calculate x from a known value of y. y is used as the public key and x as the private key. For all encryption methods with a public key, the absence of other methods has not been mathematically strictly proven; the calculation of the private key by brute force. Cryptosystems with public keys differ in the form of one-way functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it is necessary to transfer information from the interlocutor to the interlocutor, a single scheme for the implementation of asymmetric encryption operates. To begin with, the first interlocutor chooses an algorithm and a pair of public and private keys. The public key is sent to the second interlocutor over an open, insecure channel. After that, the second interlocutor encrypts the information using the sent public key and sends the received cipher back to the first interlocutor, who decrypts the message using the private key created at the beginning. At the same time, if it is necessary to establish a communication channel in both directions, then operations before decrypting messages are performed by both interlocutors. Thus, everyone will know their private, public keys and the public key of the interlocutor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, if we denote by EA the public key of the interlocutor A, by DA the private key of the interlocutor A, then v=EA(u) is the result of encrypting the message u, and u=DA(v) is the result of decrypting the message v. In this case, the transformations must be such that for any u the equality DA(EA(u))=u holds true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public key cryptography is used as an independent means of protecting information, as well as a means of distributing keys, and as a means of user authentication. However, like any system, this encryption method has its advantages and disadvantages relative to symmetric encryption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantages include the absence of the need to transfer the secret key over a reliable channel and the knowledge of the decryption key by only one of the interlocutors. In addition, in large networks, the number of keys will be significantly less than in a symmetrical system.
The disadvantages include the complexity of making changes to the algorithm, longer keys, a slower process of encrypting and decrypting a message, and the need for more computing resources to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at some of the most famous systems based on encryption using a public key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1977, scientists at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology developed the RSA encryption algorithm based on the factorization problem (the factorization problem). This system was named RSA after the first letters of the names of scientists and became the first algorithm suitable for both encryption and digital signature.
In this algorithm, prime numbers p and q are chosen, which are kept secret, and only their product N=p*q and the encryption key (public key) are published. The private key, that is, the decryption key, is secret and is generated using knowledge of the factorization of the numbers N (that is, knowledge of p and q).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ElGamal system is based on the difficulty of computing discrete logarithms in finite fields. Includes encryption algorithm and digital signature algorithm. The scheme was proposed by Taher El-Gamal in 1984. In fact, he developed one of the variants of the Diffie-Hellman algorithm .: he improved the system and received two algorithms that were used for encryption and for authentication. But ElGamal&amp;rsquo;s algorithm was not patented and therefore became a cheaper alternative, as there were no license fees to pay. The algorithm is believed to be covered by the Diffie-Hellman patent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McEliece&amp;rsquo;s system is based on algebraic coding theory (decoding of complete linear codes) and was the first scheme to use randomization in the encryption process. Designed by Robert McAlice in 1978.
For the private key, a binary error-correcting Gopp code is chosen, for which an efficient decoding algorithm (Peterson&amp;rsquo;s algorithm) is known. The public key is obtained by disguising the selected code as a complete linear one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I want to say that asymmetric encryption is more secure than symmetric encryption. Public key cryptographic systems are currently widely used in various network protocols, in particular, in the TLS protocols and its predecessor SSL (underlying HTTPS), in SSH. Also used in PGP, S/MIME.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel and Serial Ports</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/ports/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/ports/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To communicate with peripheral devices, one or more I/O controller chips are connected to the computer bus. The main function of a port is to act as a connection point where a cable is connected from a peripheral device and to allow data to be transferred from one device to another. Usually, it is the very end of the connector located on the motherboard that is called the port. Any computer must have a minimum set of ports, without which operation is impossible - these are ports for connecting a monitor, mouse, keyboard, a network connection connector, a universal USB port and an audio connector for a sound card. If necessary, the number of computer ports can be increased using expansion boards connected to the main board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ports can be divided into two types - serial and parallel. They are divided depending on the type used for communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serial ports (also called COM port) are ports through which peripheral devices are connected using a serial protocol. In other words, information is transmitted through them one bit at a time, bit by bit. The name &amp;ldquo;serial port&amp;rdquo; is assigned to a port that has the RS-232C standard, so although other interfaces (such as USB) also use a serial method of exchange, they are not classified as serial ports. Serial connectors typically have 9 to 25 pins, and a personal computer typically has one to four serial ports. Serial ports are usually built into the motherboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A feature of serial ports compared to other &amp;ldquo;serial&amp;rdquo; technologies (such as USB or Ethernet) is the presence of time requirements only between bits of one byte (baud rate is the time gap between them). There are no timing requirements between the 2 bytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, the serial port was used to connect the terminal, later it was used for the modem and mouse. Serial ports are now rarely used, as they are unsuitable for entertainment and office purposes. However, they are indispensable for applications, so they are mainly used to connect to uninterruptible power supplies, to communicate with hardware for the development of embedded computing systems, satellite receivers, as well as with devices for security systems of objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parallel ports are ports through which communication between a computer and its peripheral device is carried out in parallel. That is, data transmission is carried out simultaneously over several communication lines or wires. Sometimes a parallel port is called a printer or Centronics port. Parallel ports are often identified in a computer system as &amp;ldquo;LPT1&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;LPT2&amp;rdquo; and, like serial ports, are built into the motherboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On personal computers, parallel ports can be used to send 8 bits simultaneously over 8 wires. Parallel ports allow you to match the low speed of an external device and the high speed of the microprocessor&amp;rsquo;s system bus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the advent of USB, the parallel port was adapted to a large number of peripherals. The first such device was dongles used to protect software from copying. Soon it began to be used with other devices - magnetic disks, scanners, modems, sound cards, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first bidirectional ports had a speed of 2.4 Mb / s. However, in order to achieve higher speeds, advanced parallel ports have been developed: ERP (Advanced Parallel Port) and EDP (Enhanced Port). RPP reaches speeds from 8 to 16 Mb / s. PRV has the same characteristics as RPP, but with the additional possibility of automatic configuration (allows the computer to recognize connected peripherals).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USB has now replaced the printer&amp;rsquo;s parallel port. Many PC and laptop manufacturers regard the parallel port as a legacy from the past and no longer support the parallel port. For example, USB to Parallel adapters have been developed and available for printers that allow you to connect printers with a parallel interface to USB ports.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
