<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Academic</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Academic</title>
      <link>https://example.com/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>https://example.com/talk/example-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/talk/example-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further event details, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page elements&lt;/a&gt; such as image galleries, can be added to the body of this page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15.05 - 21.05</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/lastweek5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 16:46:14 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/lastweek5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past week has been normal. The session is coming up, so a lot of study.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encryption</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/shifr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 13:09:14 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/shifr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Encryption is the transformation of information in order to hide it from unauthorized persons. It is with the help of encryption that three states of information security are provided: confidentiality, integrity and identifiability. In any encryption algorithm, the key is important - it approves the choice of a particular transformation. An encryption key is a set of numbers and letters used by an algorithm to encrypt and decrypt information. The strength of the key depends on its length in bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Encryption can be symmetrical or asymmetric. Symmetric encryption uses the same key for both encryption and decryption. And with asymmetric encryption (encryption with a public key), the encryption and decryption keys are different, which makes this option more reliable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific programming languages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 13:09:21 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/languages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you know, there are many scientific programming languages in the world. In this post, we will talk a little about the most famous and used languages in various fields of science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One important language is Bash, an updated Unix shell first released in the late 80s. Server configuration scripts are usually written in Bash. Applications: server administration, CLI tools, DevOps, virtualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COBOL belongs to one of the oldest but still used languages. It was created by Grace Hopper in the late 1950s and was intended to standardize the development of large-scale business applications on computers. An incredible 95% of ATM transactions go through COBOL systems, with many of these devices operating 24 hours a day, 365 days a year. Applications: banking/finance, international corporations, governments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most powerful and fastest languages are C/C++. C was created in the early 1970s by Dennis Ritchie, C++ was developed by Bjorn Stroustrup in 1985. C and C++ are well suited for demanding applications that value low-level hardware access and performance. Applications: OS/SDK development, embedded devices, game engines, science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dart is a fairly modern programming language developed by Google for creating mobile, desktop, web and server applications. Dart provides a rich set of features suitable for defining complex interactions, asynchronous operations, animations, and more. Applications: cross-platform applications, cloud services/corporate systems, games, graphics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortran was created in the 1950s by John Backus to carry out scientific and engineering work. Applications: aerospace/defense, scientific computing, numerical analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JavaScript was developed by Brandon Eich in the 90s to add scripting to websites. Today it is a universal web interface language with powerful, standardized features that are supported by all major browsers. Applications: full-stack development, cloud services/container storage, games, utilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is impossible not to mention Python - one of the most famous languages, not even in the circle of programmers. This language is well established and will remain one of the most requested tools for a long time to come. Applications: artificial intelligence/machine learning, data mining, cloud services/web, media, scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last language I would like to touch on is SQL. This language belongs to the universal programming languages and is a powerful domain-specific language for managing relational databases. Advanced skills allow the developer to create extremely secure and robust domain rules that are independent of the programming language or SDK used. High profile implementations include Microsoft SQL Server, Oracle Database, and PostgreSQL. Each of them has a unique extension of the SQL language and offers new features that go beyond the core SQL specification. Applications: working with relational data, embedding data in applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01.05 - 07.05</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/lastweek4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 13:08:21 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/lastweek4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Due to the approach of the session, there was a lot of study and work. I continued to work on the site, completed the penultimate laboratory work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Encryption</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/cripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/cripts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In public-key encryption, each party creates a pair of keys, a public key and a private key. These keys are linked to each other, so a message encrypted with the public key can only be decrypted with the corresponding private key.
An important point is that when creating keys, it is possible to generate very large numbers in such a way that, knowing the public key, it is impossible to calculate the private key in any way. Thus, ensuring reliable encryption of messages is based on the knowledge of the private key exclusively by its owner. The idea of asymmetric encryption is based on a complex mathematical question that allows you to build one-way functions. Given x, the function y = f(x) is easily determined. But at the same time, it is very difficult to calculate x from a known value of y. y is used as the public key and x as the private key. For all encryption methods with a public key, the absence of other methods has not been mathematically strictly proven; the calculation of the private key by brute force. Cryptosystems with public keys differ in the form of one-way functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it is necessary to transfer information from the interlocutor to the interlocutor, a single scheme for the implementation of asymmetric encryption operates. To begin with, the first interlocutor chooses an algorithm and a pair of public and private keys. The public key is sent to the second interlocutor over an open, insecure channel. After that, the second interlocutor encrypts the information using the sent public key and sends the received cipher back to the first interlocutor, who decrypts the message using the private key created at the beginning. At the same time, if it is necessary to establish a communication channel in both directions, then operations before decrypting messages are performed by both interlocutors. Thus, everyone will know their private, public keys and the public key of the interlocutor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, if we denote by EA the public key of the interlocutor A, by DA the private key of the interlocutor A, then v=EA(u) is the result of encrypting the message u, and u=DA(v) is the result of decrypting the message v. In this case, the transformations must be such that for any u the equality DA(EA(u))=u holds true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public key cryptography is used as an independent means of protecting information, as well as a means of distributing keys, and as a means of user authentication. However, like any system, this encryption method has its advantages and disadvantages relative to symmetric encryption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantages include the absence of the need to transfer the secret key over a reliable channel and the knowledge of the decryption key by only one of the interlocutors. In addition, in large networks, the number of keys will be significantly less than in a symmetrical system.
The disadvantages include the complexity of making changes to the algorithm, longer keys, a slower process of encrypting and decrypting a message, and the need for more computing resources to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at some of the most famous systems based on encryption using a public key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1977, scientists at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology developed the RSA encryption algorithm based on the factorization problem (the factorization problem). This system was named RSA after the first letters of the names of scientists and became the first algorithm suitable for both encryption and digital signature.
In this algorithm, prime numbers p and q are chosen, which are kept secret, and only their product N=p*q and the encryption key (public key) are published. The private key, that is, the decryption key, is secret and is generated using knowledge of the factorization of the numbers N (that is, knowledge of p and q).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ElGamal system is based on the difficulty of computing discrete logarithms in finite fields. Includes encryption algorithm and digital signature algorithm. The scheme was proposed by Taher El-Gamal in 1984. In fact, he developed one of the variants of the Diffie-Hellman algorithm .: he improved the system and received two algorithms that were used for encryption and for authentication. But ElGamal&amp;rsquo;s algorithm was not patented and therefore became a cheaper alternative, as there were no license fees to pay. The algorithm is believed to be covered by the Diffie-Hellman patent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McEliece&amp;rsquo;s system is based on algebraic coding theory (decoding of complete linear codes) and was the first scheme to use randomization in the encryption process. Designed by Robert McAlice in 1978.
For the private key, a binary error-correcting Gopp code is chosen, for which an efficient decoding algorithm (Peterson&amp;rsquo;s algorithm) is known. The public key is obtained by disguising the selected code as a complete linear one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I want to say that asymmetric encryption is more secure than symmetric encryption. Public key cryptographic systems are currently widely used in various network protocols, in particular, in the TLS protocols and its predecessor SSL (underlying HTTPS), in SSH. Also used in PGP, S/MIME.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel and Serial Ports</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/ports/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/ports/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To communicate with peripheral devices, one or more I/O controller chips are connected to the computer bus. The main function of a port is to act as a connection point where a cable is connected from a peripheral device and to allow data to be transferred from one device to another. Usually, it is the very end of the connector located on the motherboard that is called the port. Any computer must have a minimum set of ports, without which operation is impossible - these are ports for connecting a monitor, mouse, keyboard, a network connection connector, a universal USB port and an audio connector for a sound card. If necessary, the number of computer ports can be increased using expansion boards connected to the main board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ports can be divided into two types - serial and parallel. They are divided depending on the type used for communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serial ports (also called COM port) are ports through which peripheral devices are connected using a serial protocol. In other words, information is transmitted through them one bit at a time, bit by bit. The name &amp;ldquo;serial port&amp;rdquo; is assigned to a port that has the RS-232C standard, so although other interfaces (such as USB) also use a serial method of exchange, they are not classified as serial ports. Serial connectors typically have 9 to 25 pins, and a personal computer typically has one to four serial ports. Serial ports are usually built into the motherboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A feature of serial ports compared to other &amp;ldquo;serial&amp;rdquo; technologies (such as USB or Ethernet) is the presence of time requirements only between bits of one byte (baud rate is the time gap between them). There are no timing requirements between the 2 bytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, the serial port was used to connect the terminal, later it was used for the modem and mouse. Serial ports are now rarely used, as they are unsuitable for entertainment and office purposes. However, they are indispensable for applications, so they are mainly used to connect to uninterruptible power supplies, to communicate with hardware for the development of embedded computing systems, satellite receivers, as well as with devices for security systems of objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parallel ports are ports through which communication between a computer and its peripheral device is carried out in parallel. That is, data transmission is carried out simultaneously over several communication lines or wires. Sometimes a parallel port is called a printer or Centronics port. Parallel ports are often identified in a computer system as &amp;ldquo;LPT1&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;LPT2&amp;rdquo; and, like serial ports, are built into the motherboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On personal computers, parallel ports can be used to send 8 bits simultaneously over 8 wires. Parallel ports allow you to match the low speed of an external device and the high speed of the microprocessor&amp;rsquo;s system bus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the advent of USB, the parallel port was adapted to a large number of peripherals. The first such device was dongles used to protect software from copying. Soon it began to be used with other devices - magnetic disks, scanners, modems, sound cards, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first bidirectional ports had a speed of 2.4 Mb / s. However, in order to achieve higher speeds, advanced parallel ports have been developed: ERP (Advanced Parallel Port) and EDP (Enhanced Port). RPP reaches speeds from 8 to 16 Mb / s. PRV has the same characteristics as RPP, but with the additional possibility of automatic configuration (allows the computer to recognize connected peripherals).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USB has now replaced the printer&amp;rsquo;s parallel port. Many PC and laptop manufacturers regard the parallel port as a legacy from the past and no longer support the parallel port. For example, USB to Parallel adapters have been developed and available for printers that allow you to connect printers with a parallel interface to USB ports.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report design</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/reportcreate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 13:09:14 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/reportcreate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use the Markdown markup language to design the report. At the beginning of the file, the number of the laboratory work on which the report is being made, the discipline and the full name of the student who completed the work is always indicated. The purpose of the work is indicated below, then each stage of working with screenshots is described step by step, a link is indicated for each screenshot. At the end of the work there is a conclusion consistent with the topic of the work, as well as answers to control questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;#&amp;rdquo; sign is used to create headers. In addition, you can format the text - to set the bold style, you need to put double asterisks on both sides of the text, for italic style - single. To create unordered lists, asterisks or dashes are used (it is possible to nest one list in another), to quote the symbol &amp;gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To generate a file from md to pdf and docs format, I use Pandoc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24.04 - 30.04</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/lastweek3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 13:08:14 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/lastweek3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past week, I wrote a mathematical analysis test, completed 12 lab, and continued developing my site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown language</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 16:48:14 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Markdown is a markup language used to create rich text using a text editor. It can be opened and modified in any text editor. Widely used for writing documentation and README files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown was created by writer and blogger John Gruber along with web activist Aaron Schwartz. They wanted to come up with the simplest and most convenient markup language with which text can be translated into a beautifully designed look. At the same time, the text must remain readable even without being reduced to a “beautiful” look. This is what Markdown turned out to be. It was created in 2004, but the language has gained the most popularity now. It is supported by a variety of blogging platforms, note-taking services, CMS, and even instant messengers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown contains basic elements that can be found in almost any README.md:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first level heading for the title;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;highlighting in bold type important parts in the description;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;link with clear text;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;second-level heading for sub-items;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a bulleted list to list the benefits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, Markdown is used for quickly formatting an article for translation into PDF, layout of a text document for placement on the site, but without the use of HTML, writing documentation for the code, making notes in a personal digital notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.04 - 9.04</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/lastweek2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 16:46:14 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/lastweek2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I wrote a test in mathematical logic, and also did a lab in the subject &amp;ldquo;Operating systems&amp;rdquo; on the topic &amp;ldquo;Emacs text editor&amp;rdquo;. In addition, we finally managed to plan a trip for the summer to friends abroad, we have already bought tickets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment (CD/CI)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/cdci/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 16:50:31 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/cdci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the context of modern development methods and DevOps, the abbreviations CI and CD are often used. CI stands for Continuous Integration and CD stands for Continuous Deployment (or Continuous Delivery).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuous Integration is a fundamental DevOps recommendation that developers regularly merge code changes into a central repository where automated builds and tests are performed. Developers who use continuous integration merge their changes back into the main branch whenever possible. Changes made by a developer are verified by creating an assembly and running automated tests on that assembly. When using continuous integration, a lot of attention is paid to test automation, as a result of which, when integrating new commits into the main branch, the application does not break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also continuous delivery - the continuation of continuous integration, since it automatically deploys all code changes, that is, not only the testing process is automated, but also the product release process. Continuous deployment goes one step further than continuous delivery - every change that goes through the production pipeline is released to customers. No human intervention is required, and only an error during a test can prevent a new change from being deployed to production. Continuous deployment is used to speed up the customer feedback cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, continuous integration is part of both continuous delivery and continuous deployment. And continuous deployment is similar to continuous delivery, except that releases happen automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main disadvantage of using continuous integration and continuous deployment is that you have to write automated tests for each new feature, improvement or bug fix. In addition, you need a continuous integration server that can monitor the main repository and automatically run tests for each new committed commit. However, there are invaluable advantages - fewer bugs get into the production environment, because of this, the release build is much easier, testing costs are reduced, and the development process is accelerated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13.03 - 18.03</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/lastweek/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 16:46:14 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/lastweek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past week has been completely normal. Passed two control - in linear algebra and mathematical analysis. In addition, I did lab work, history homework, and did some work in my spare time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example preprint / working paper</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/preprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/preprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code, math, and images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://example.com/slides/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/slides/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-slides-in-markdown-with-wowchemy&#34;&gt;Create slides in Markdown with Wowchemy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wowchemy&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/slides/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/pdf-export/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;porridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;porridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Eating...&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  Three
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Only the speaker can read these notes
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Press &lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;`S`&lt;/span&gt; key to view
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  {{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/media/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;background-image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;/media/boards.jpg&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;#0000FF&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;my-style&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34; data-lang=&#34;css&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;kc&#34;&gt;navy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/z8wNYzb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/slides/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example journal article</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/journal-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/journal-article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code, math, and images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example conference paper</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/conference-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/conference-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code, math, and images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://example.com/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
